booksdirect.co.uk 2009-05-25

# Books Direct - Privacy Policy

Privacy Statement

BCA respects the privacy concerns of users of its web sites and is registered under the relevant Data Protection legislation.  
In order to provide you with the best service we can, BCA has made it its policy to monitor the use of its websites and collect certain personal information. When you register to use a BCA website, BCA will store your e-mail address along with any other information you may provide. When you use the services on the website, we may need to collect further information about you. This information may include, but is not limited to, details such as your name, address and your credit card details.  
We may use the information provided to process any transactions undertaken by you and for internal administration and analysis. We disclose your information to third parties for the purpose of administration and providing services to you.  
From time to time we may employ a third party to send out e-mail campaigns and to serve cookies and pixel tags. The information may also be used to notify you of products and services, including those of third parties where you have opted to receive information by email about third party offers, which may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive such offers, please advise BCA in writing.  
By disclosing your personal information to BCA, you agree to collection, storage and processing of your personal information in the manner set out here.

**Cookies**

We only employ session cookies to store the necessary transaction information during one visit. Cookies are small files that are sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard disc. Whenever you visit your club website, and unless you have changed the settings in your browser so as not to accept cookies, then your computer will store an identifying code in the cookie which may mean you do not need to type your user_name into the member login box each time you return to the site. Other than this, we store a 'Session ID' which helps us to determine if you have logged into your club website. These IDs are highly encrypted and have no direct correlation with your personal data. We do not store your password or any other information in the cookie, or use it for any other purpose. Our third-party advertisers may place or recognise a unique cookie on your browser. You can at any time set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies. This may impair your experience of your club website, but will not prevent you from maintaining your account or placing orders.  
From time to time we may employ a third party to send out e-mail campaigns that uses cookies and pixels to track the emails that we send you and we may use this information to notify you of products and services that may be of interest to you. The cookies we use for these emails collect information based on your email and purchasing from email behaviour only. If you wish to find out more about the use of cookies and the information-gathering practices and how to opt-out of such tracking please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.net/privacypolicy).

**What will you do with my e-mail address?**

By providing BCA or a third party website with your email address you consent to receive emails from us about our latest products and special offers which we think may be of interest to you. Our emails refer to the products & services we offer - including books, CDs and other services.  BCA will send you no more than two emails in a 7 day period, where you have expressed more than one interest.

**Can I unsubscribe from e-mails?**

All subscribers have the option to opt-out of receiving marketing emails from us at any time. If you do not wish to receive marketing emails from us we recommend you opt-out by using the link at the foot of the email.  All requests to unsubscribe will normally be processed within 7 days. Members can unsubscribe by going to 'My Account' and clicking on 'Email Preferences'.

**Do you trade under any other names?**

BCA, also known as Books Direct operates a variety of brands. For a listing of our book club and other brands, please see [www.bca.co.uk](http://www.bca.co.uk/). BCA may also from time to time launch new brands. Upon launch this listing of our brands will be updated. If you have any queries regarding this privacy statement please go to the Contact Us page where you can find several ways of submitting your questions. Alternatively, please e-mail [privacypolicy@bca.co.uk](mailto:privacypolicy@bca.co.uk).  
BCA is registered under the Data Protection Act (Reg no Z6100513) and this shows the purpose, source and disclosure terms of the data held.  
BCA is a full member of the Direct Marketing Association (DMA). Should you have any observations or concerns you would like to bring to our attention to help us improve our service, then please let us know.

Email address: [departmentdma@bca.co.uk](mailto:departmentdma@bca.co.uk "mailto:departmentdma@bca.co.uk")[](mailto:DMA@bca.co.uk)

### Visiting from Another Website

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. If you would like more information about this practice and your choices, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp). 

Company Details

**Company Name**

Your book club is owned by BCA, a partnership of:

Book Club Associates Limited, registration 2094795

and

Book Club Trading Limited 

registration number: 3528183 

England registered office: 1 Fleet Place, London EC4 7 WS for both Book Club Associates Ltd and Book Club Trading Ltd.

**Address**

BCA, Hargreaves Road, Groundwell, Swindon, SN99 9XX, England
